# **COLLEEN HIGGINS**

Seattle, WA

colleenhiggins87@gmail.com

### WEB DEVELOPER

Github LinkedIn Portfolio

## Summary

Full-stack web developer who is equally thrilled by back and front end code. Proficient in mobile-first responsive design and test-driven development. Experience with modern tooling, unbelievable work ethic and a strong drive to continue to grow and learn.

### Skills

Front End: JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML, CSS3, Git, GitHub, RESTful APIs, Jest, Enzyme, accessible design (a11y)

Back End: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Knex, Mocha, Chai, Asynchronous Programming

Related: Pair-programming, written & verbal communication, leadership, Linux, Windows, Mac, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, zeit

# **Recent Projects**

<u>Symptom Tracker</u>: <u>GitHub front end</u>, <u>GitHub back end</u> solution for people looking to find patterns in food sensitivity. Built with JS, React, Node, PostgreSQL.

<u>SpacedRepetition</u>: <u>GitHub front end</u>, <u>GitHub back end</u> uses linked lists to help learn Italian. Built with JS, React, Node, PostgreSQL.

AMRApp: Github front-end, Github back-end random workout generator. Built with JS, React, Node, PostgreSQL.

# Experience

Thinkful February 2019 - Present

## Software Engineering Apprentice

- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer, and daily paired programming with classmates and instructors.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, PostgreSQL, algorithms & data structures.

EvergreenHealth Medical Center

Kirkland, WA

## Acute Care Physical Therapist

October 2017 – June 2019

- Managed full caseload of patients with primarily neurological and complex medical diagnoses including collaboration with medical teams for optimizing patient outcomes and safe discharge planning
- Initiated and created processes for ARU including best-practices with outcome measures, documentation, scheduling and work-flow
- Responsible for scheduling therapists on weekend rotations and coordination of care with nurses and MDs on weekends

Northeast Rehab Hospital

Salem, NH

#### **Outpatient Physical Therapist**

February 2017 – September 2017

- Managed full caseload of patients with orthopedic and medical diagnoses, including evaluation and prescreening for appropriateness of interventions
- Successfully implemented system for training rehab aides including document for clarity on roles and common exercises

Rocky Mountain Youth Conservation Corps- **Field Crew Leader**, Steamboat Springs, CO April 2012-October 2012 Chesapeake Conservation Corps-**Trash Free Schools Program Assistant**, Accokeek, MD November 2010-November 2011 Montana Conservation Corps-**Field Crew Leader**, Helena, MT February 2010-November 2010

### Education

MGH Institute of Health Professions

**Doctor of Physical Therapy** 

December 2016

GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

Elon University

B.S of Environmental Studies, B.A Biology, Minor Political Science

GPA: 3.65 / 4.0

May 2009